Benawi, I trust you already know the
reason I have summoned you?
ベナウィ
おみゃあの呼ばれた理由
もう分かってるにゃも？
Is it regarding the insurrection?
反乱の件にございますか？
ふううー
I will have them exterminated.
奴らを根絶やしにするにゃーも
With all due respect, sire...
-聖上 恐れながら…
-女子供とて容赦はいらん
No need to show any mercy on
the women or children either!
Make it a complete massacre!
Spare no one!
１人残らず皆殺しにゃーも
I wonder if it would not be prudent to send
an envoy to speak with them first?
まずは使者を送り その者達と
話し合いをなさるべきかと
Speak with them!? Get real!
話し合い？
ふざけるなにゃも！
They killed my little brother!
あいつらは弟を殺したにゃもよ！
It won't be enough to satisfy me even if
we tear them limb from limb!
八つ裂きにしても収まらんにゃも！
However, without the people, the country...
ですが 民あっての…
That's enough! Enough, enough!
くどい くどい くどい！
This country does not depend on the people!
民あっての國ではない！
The people depend on this country!
國あっての民にゃも
And the country...
そして 國は！
is mine alone!
このインカラ自身にゃも
Sire...
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空 果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に 充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼（はね）を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ 行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから 一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
おーい そっち気をつけろー
Daughter of the Forest
大丈夫か？
うお あたぁ かっ かあ だっ！
Please do not overdo it.
無理をしないでください
Hey, I can't just leave all the
work up to you young'uns.
若いもんだけに
任せておくわけにゃいかないだに
いっひっひっ
The fence is done, Hakuoro-san!
ハクオロさん
柵の方終わりました！ うっ
Ah, good work.
ああ ご苦労さま
The enemy will be here before long.
いずれ敵が来る
And I'm sure everyone is tired out as well.
皆も疲れているだろうが
You need to make sure that you
get some rest too, Hakuoro-san.
ハクオロさんこそ
ちゃんと休んでくださいよ
Right.
Father!
お父さーん！
ガアァー！
-ふーふふ　ふう
-おーっと
Here, I'll bet you're hungry, right?
はい　お腹すいたでしょ？
えっへっへっ
Thanks!
どうも
-うん んん…
-どうぞ
Here you go.
I handed portions out to everyone.
皆さんの分 配り終わりました
Good, thank you.
ああ ありがとう
Sure!
はい
Father, I handed them out too.
お父さん アルルゥも配った
Did you? That's super!
そうか　偉いぞ
-ふふぅ　ふう
-ウガァ　ガァ
お前も手伝ったんだな
You helped out too, didn't you?
Way to go.
偉いぞ
Mukkuru!
ムックル！
-ひぃ　あ？
-ワウ ワァ　ヒュグ…
What's the matter?
うん？ どうしたんだ？
ムックル お腹すいたって
Mukkuru says he's hungry.
-ヒュグ
-だーめ　さっき食べたでしょ？
No, you already ate before, right?
グウゥ…
あっはは　すっかりお母さんだな
A mother through and through!
ごめんね　どうしても
足りなくなっちゃうから
I'm sorry,
but we'd end up not having enough left.
ワハ
-ワアァーウ
-わあ はっ！
うっ　やーだ くすぐったい！ ほっ
No, stop! That tickles!
はあ　はあっ！ ムックル
だめだってば！ うっ ふう うう うはっ
I said no, Mukkuru!
ウグウゥー
ワァーウ
うっ　どしたの？
What is it?
He says he feels sorry for you.
可哀想って
Sorry for me?
か 可哀想…
ウグゥ ウウ…
Feels BAD for me...
可哀想って…
There, there.
いい子 いい子ぉ
こいつが終わったら
今度裏の方やっとかないとなあ
-うん んっ うん
-さて エルルゥ
Okay, Eruruu, and you too, Aruruu.
-それにアルルゥ
-うん？ んっ
This place will soon become a battleground.
もうすぐ ここは戦場になる
The two of you should return to the village.
２人は村に戻った方がいい
You understand, don't you?
分かってくれるな？
No.
嫌です
This really will be a dangerous place to...
本当に ここは危険に
そんなこと分かってます
I know that.
Then...
だったら
That's why!
だから
I'm staying with you, Father!
お父さんと一緒
But Tuskuru-san would not have...
しかし それでは
トゥスクルさんに…
申し訳が 立たない
It would be inexcusable.
ほら それに私達が帰ったら
ご飯がおいしくなくなって
Hey, another thing is that if we go back,
the food won't be any good anymore.
Plus, all the laundry will sit and
get dirtier and start to stink.
それから洗濯物が汚れて
辺りが臭くなって
And then...
それから
それから…
うっふ
I guess I have no choice then.
仕方ないな
Father!
お父さん！
ワアァーウ
ふっふぅ　きゃっほー
Whoopee!
ふふふ ふっふっ ふふ　ふふっふ
Someone moving?
引っ越し？
あれ 全部 荷物なの？
Is that all somebody's luggage?
Yuzuha?
Did ya see that?
-ユズハ
-今の見たか？
Is she like some princess?
どっかのお姫様か？
Oboro, what is the meaning of this?
オボロ これはいったい
You have saved my life twice.
俺は あんたに二度も命を救われた
Thus it is fitting I devote it to you.
ならばこの命 あんたに捧げるのが道理
My life was once forfeit.
Now, do with me as you wish!
一度は捨てた命だ
好きに使ってくれ
Forget it.
だめだ
I will not take along anyone who
values his own life so little!
自分の命を軽んじる者を
連れていくわけにはいかない
Oboro, promise me that you will not go off
risking your life all alone, okay?
オボロ
もう１人で死地に赴くような
真似はしないと 約束してくれるな？
Brother...
兄者…
I vow, my brother, that I will stay with you
俺はディネボクシリまで
兄者と共に在ることを誓う！
wherever you go,
even into the fires of Dinebokushiri!
ハクオロ様と共に！
Together with Hakuoro-sama!
Tuskuru-sama?
トゥスクル様？
へっ はあ！ あっ ちが…
No, it's not...
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
You see, you have the same
scent as Tuskuru-sama.
トゥスクル様と同じ香りがしましたから
あっ は… おばあちゃんの…
Grandma's...
My name is Eruruu.
私 エルルゥって言います
Hakuoro-san asked me to come
and check up on you.
ハクオロさんに言われて
様子を見に来ました
I see.
そうですか
あの
Say, who is that behind you?
後ろの方は？
Huh?
Aruruu!
アルルゥ
Nice to meet you.
初めまして
Come on, that's no way to talk!
Introduce yourself properly!
こら んじゃないでしょ
ちゃんとご挨拶しなさい
うふ ふっ
It doesn't seem like you're
running a temperature.
熱は無いみたいですね
What's wrong?
どうしたんです？
It really is just like Tuskuru-sama's.
本当にトゥスクル様みたい
The warm scent of different kinds of herbs...
いろんな草と温かな香り
The same scent as Tuskuru-sama.
トゥスクル様と同じ香り
Well, Yuzuha-san...
あの ユズハさん
My grandma...
おばあちゃんは…
はい　お兄様から聞きました
Yes, I heard about it from my brother.
最初に こっちへ来たいって言ったのは
あいつの方なんだ
She actually said she wanted
to come here first.
Yuzuha did?
ユズハが？
At first, I also said to forget it.
はじめは俺もだめだと言った
But she wouldn't let up.
だが あいつは引き下がらなかった
And she's never spoken up and
voiced her opinion before.
今まで一度も自分の気持ちを
口にしたことがなかった あいつが
だったら俺は あいつの
好きにさせてやろうと思った
That's why I thought I'd do as she wished.
If we become too much of a burden,
I won't object if you throw us out.
もし足手まといになるようなら
捨てても構わん
She is also prepared for it,
if that's what you decide.
それは あいつも覚悟の上だ
So please allow me to grant her wish.
だから あいつの好きにさせてやってくれ
This is the first time she's
ever been so willful.
初めてなんだ
あいつが わがままを言ったのは
So, anyway, brother...
で 兄者
What is it you're writing there?
そいつは何を書いてるんだ？
Ah, well, I thought I would request assistance
from the neighboring villages.
近隣の集落に
助力を要請しようと思ってな
But none of them will want to get wrapped up in
something this dangerous, don't you think?
どこも やばいことには
巻き込まれたくないんじゃないか？
Even if it is only a few, if there are people
who will side with us, then...
だが わずかでも
同調してくれる者達がいるのなら
Well, brother, if that's how you put it...
兄者が そう言うのなら
Tell me, Oboro...
なあ オボロ
What's with you calling me brother?
その 兄者というのは何だ？
あーあ？
You saved my life, and I'm entrusting
Yuzuha and everything to you.
命を救われてユズハを 全てを委ねるんだ
It's only natural that I should
call you brother!
兄と呼ぶのは当然！
Ah, right...
よし　えいっ
ふっ ふっ うっ　せいやああー！
What's the matter? Ya creampuffs!
何だよ　だらしがねえなあ
It doesn't look like the enemy's coming anyway.
敵も来ないようだしよお
You frickin' idiot! We're doing this training
because we don't know when they'll come!
バカ野郎　いつ来るか
分かんねえから訓練してんだろうが
We'll be done in before we even get into battle!
戦う前に参っちまうよ
If that's your attitude, then you'll
be the first to go down.
んなこと言ってっと
真っ先に殺されちまうぞ
ふへぇ… おい
Right...
おい
ひいっ！
なああ
Sorry, I didn't expect to see you.
すまない
あんたとは思わなかった
It's all right.
ああ いいえ
ハクオロさんが オボロさんは
ここにいるからって
Hakuoro-san told me you'd be here.
So my brother already knew, huh?
兄者には お見通しか
You shouldn't overwork yourself.
あまり根を詰めない方が
Oboro-san?
オボロさん？
Oh, uh, sorry.
いや すまない
All clear to the south and to the west!
南方 西方 異常なーし！
All clear to the north and to the east!
北方 東方 異常なーし！
It's our honored brother.
兄者様だ
What's wrong?
どうしたんです？
My figures for the provisions
just do not add up.
どうも食料の計算が合わないんだ
Oh...
Aruruu!?
アルルゥ！
What in the world are you doing out here?
もう 何してるの？ こんな所で
Uh...
グルッ グッ…
Aruruu, move aside now!
アルルゥ ちょっとどきなさい！
No!
だめ！
I'm not taking no for an answer.
だめじゃないでしょ
Now, show us what's in there.
No!
-さあ 中を見せて
-やーあーだ！
グウゥ…
Is that Mukkuru!?
これ ムックル？
When did he ever get so big?
いつの間にこんな
-グッフゥ
-アルルゥ！
Aruruu!
グゥーウ
What do you think you're doing!?
あなたって子は何てことするの！
うん… ムックル お腹すいた
Mukkuru is hungry.
You do understand how important our
food is to us right now, don't you?
アルルゥも 今は食べ物が
どんなに大切か分かってるでしょ？
But...
だって…
No buts about it!
だってじゃないの！
-グルルル…！ ウゥ…
-あん？
Uh, hey, Eruruu...
なあ エルルゥ
I think it's all right now.
そのくらいで いいんじゃないか？
十分 反省してるんだろ？
You are sorry for what you've
done, aren't you?
Let's figure out what we can do about
feeding Mukkuru, all right?
ムックルのことは これから考えよう
あは！
-グル グウ グウ
-お おい
Hey!
Father!
お父さん
-あっ こら！
-はっ はあ　んっ　んー！
Mukkuru!
You're too easy on Aruruu!
ハクオロさんは
アルルゥを甘やかしすぎです！
I do not mean to...
いや そう言われても ですね　だあ！
Yeah, I guess I am.
じゃあ 後を頼みます
Okay, the rest is up to you.
おう 任せときな
Yeah, you just leave it to me!
Hakuoro-san!
ハクオロさん
Be careful.
気をつけて
Right.
Come on.
さあ ほら
Take me with you, Father!
お父さん アルルゥも！
I am glad you feel that way, but you
be a good girl and wait here.
気持ちは嬉しいが
いい子で待ってるんだぞ
Aruruu!
アルルゥ！
グルルル… グオオー！
You don't have to come along
yourself, you know!
何も 兄者自ら赴かなくても
As you may become involved in a fight,
it is only fitting I go too.
いや 戦いに巻き込もうというのだ
ならば こちらから赴くのが礼儀だ
It'll be an even bigger problem
if anything happens to you.
兄者に何かあったら その方が問題だ！
That is exactly why I am having you come along.
だからこそ お前についてきてもらった
Well, that's okay then.
なら いいんだ
うっひひひ
Brother!
兄者！
What is it?
どうした？
うう うっ　てやっ！
This is...
これは…
It's awful.
ひでえ…
Hey, what happened here!?
おい どうした！
うっ うう　あいつら…
Those bastards...
How could they?
何てことを…
うっ ふう ふふぅ ふふふ　うっ ふう…
You sons of bitches!
きぃーさーまああー！
Wait!
待て
Don't stop me, brother!
止めるな 兄者！
I told you to wait.
待てと言ったぞ
I am Benawi.
私はベナウィ
I serve Emperor Inkalla, ruler of Kenashkolpe.
ケナシコウルペ皇
インカラに仕える者です
You're the leader of the rebel force, correct?
あなたが賊軍の長ですね？
Your actions have brought on this situation.
あなたが始めたことが
このような事態を招きました
Why did you attack a village that had
no involvement in any of this?
なぜ関係の無い集落を襲った
As an example,
見せしめ のつもりでしょうか
I would imagine.
Don't play innocent!
とぼけるな！
貴様らが やったことだろうが！
This was your own doing!
Hey, now wait a minute!
おい ちょっと待てよ
Please drop your weapons and surrender.
どうか武器を捨てて 投降してください
We have no desire to fight.
我々は戦いを望んでいない
Brother!
兄者！
However...
だが
That is unfortunate.
残念です
うああー！ うぅあ！
Brother!
兄者ー！
さああー！
I'm your opponent!
お前の相手は
俺だあ！
-でやっ！
-うっ…
Bastard...
てめえ…
-せい！
-おわっ！
Now!
へっ へっへえ
たあっ！
Brother!
兄者様ー！
うおおおー！ はっ はっ はっ
てや！ やああー！ はっ はっ
Prepare!
行きます
うう 兄者！
Brother!
ふっ　ははあー！
Stop lookin' away!
よそ見してんじゃねえぞ！
Brother!
兄者様！
ドリィ！
Dori!
Brother!
兄者！
-ふん！
-うわっ！
Thought I told you to stop lookin' away.
よそ見してんじゃねえって言ってんだろ
You seem to be rather strong,
筋はいいようですが
but this is as far as you go.
これまでです
ガァオオオー！
What's going on?
何だ？
-ガァオオオー！
-ああっ　うう！
You leave my father alone!
お父さんを いじめるなあー！
Aruruu!
アルルゥ！
You gotta be kidding me!
冗談だろ？
That's Father's enemy!
お父さんの敵！
-グウゥ… ワァオオオー！
-ムティカパ？
Mutikapa!?
Whoa, whoa, now that's playin' dirty!
おいおい そりゃ反則だぜ
Aruruu-sama!
アルルゥ様
Tell me one, no, two things
１つ
いえ ２つだけ聞かせてください
Do you believe what you are doing is right?
あなたは自分がしていることが
正しいと信じていますか？
You're damn right it is!
当たり前だ！
義は俺達にある
We're doing what's right!
Brother?
兄者？
If the nethermost depths of hell,
if Dinebokushiri really does exist,
もし地獄の底
ディネボクシリというものがあるのなら
I imagine that is where I will fall.
私は そこに落ちるだろうな
Is that your answer?
それが答えですか
What is the other thing?
もう１つは？
Your name.
あなたの名を
Hakuoro.
ハクオロ
Hakuoro... I shall remember that name.
その名 覚えておきましょう
Until we meet again, on the battlefield.
いずれまた 戦で
Bastard!
野郎…
Brother!
兄者！
あいつら よくもこんな真似を…
How dare they do such a thing!?
This was not their doing.
これは奴らの仕業じゃない
What is more, that skirmish just now...
それに今の戦い
was to put us to the test.
試されていた
That man is not what you think he is.
あの男… あんなものではあるまい
But this will greatly alter the course of battle.
だが これで戦況が大きく変わる
The villages who previously thought
themselves uninvolved
このことで傍観を決め込んでいた集落も
will come to ally themselves
with the other side.
向こうから合流してくるだろう
Never know what tomorrow will bring, huh?
あすは我が身… か
I'm even using Tuskuru-san's death as
a means to manipulate people.
私は この惨事ですら
駆け引きの道具にしようとしている
Could a man like that ever be called righteous?
そんな男が正しいと言えるか
Brother!
兄者
It's just as he said.
あの男の言ったとおりだ
If I had not caused the revolt,
none of this would have happened.
反乱など起こさなければ
こんなことにはならなかった
Brother...
兄者…
Do you think that kind of attitude
兄者がそんなことで
will help you set a good example for the people
to believe in you and support your cause!?
信じて ついてくる奴らに
示しがつくと思っているのか！
Oboro...
オボロ
I guess you are right.
そうだな
This is the last time I will say something like that.
こんなことを言うのは これで最後だ
クゥーウ ウー ウゥー
We were able to cheat death thanks to you.
お前のおかげで 命拾いした
It was because you didn't yell at him yesterday.
昨日 お父さん叱らなかったから
Is that right? Thank you.
そっか　ありがとう
グルル… ウーウゥ ウゥー ウー
Now then... Aruruu, I am afraid I must scold you.
さて アルルゥ
しかし私は アルルゥを
叱らなければならない
I thought I told you to stay at
home and wait for me.
うちで待っていろと言っただろ？
ガアアァー！
ぶはあー
So, you lose to those rebels and
return here in defeat, eh?
おみゃあ 例の賊どもに
負けて帰ってきたにゃも？
I am truly sorry.
申し訳ございません
You are scorned by the ignorant masses
because you are such a coward!
おみゃあが そんな腰抜けだから
愚民どもに舐められるにゃもよ
I would like to ask you a question,
if I may be so bold.
恐れながら お伺いします
Yeah, what?
にゃーも
As I suspected, putting that
village to the torch was...
やはり あの集落の炎は…
刃向かうとどうなるか 見せしめにゃも
Defy me, and what do you think will happen?
They were a lesson to the others!
You have lost your edge, so I am
giving him your post.
おみゃあがトロトロしているから
こいつに やらせたにゃも
From now on, Nuwangi here will fill
the role of samurai general.
このヌワンギを 今日から
侍大将の任に就かせるにゃも
つまり おみゃあは
That means you're finished.
お払い箱にゃも
へっはははは　ベナウィさん
Pleased to meet ya, Benawi-san!
よろしく
はははははあー！ はははあー！
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
孤独の中求む
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
魂から結びつき 私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼 祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼 弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす 輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし 詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
Gathering Force